A Guide to the Arthur Robert Smith Collection, 1981-2009
The Edgar Cayce Foundation
The Edgar Cayce Foundation
Arthur Robert Smith Collection, 1981-2009
The Edgar Cayce Foundation, Virginia Beach, Virginia
Coll. 36
0.8 Linear Feet 2 boxes.
Smith, Arthur Robert
Arrangement
Collection is arranged alphabetically by material type.
Biographical / Historical
Arthur Robert Smith was born on February 13, 1925 in York, Pennsylvania to S. Arthur Smith and Inez Smith. He served in the United States Navy from 1943 to 1946. Smith married Yvonne Franklin in 1946, Doris Elizabeth McDowell in 1967, and Jane Dreifus in 1993. He had four children.
He worked as a columnist, correspondent and reporter during his sixty-year career in journalism. He served as the editorial editor for the Virginian-Pilot in Norfolk, Virginia. Smith wrote ten books on political and spiritual topics, including About My Father's Business (1988), on the life of Hugh Lynn Cayce. Smith also founded Venture Inward Magazine for the Association for Research and Enlightenment in 1984.
Smith died in Virginia Beach on November 15, 2016 at the age of 91.
Scope and Contents
This collection includes correspondence, interview transcripts, notes, and research sources collected by Arthur Robert Smith to write the book entitled About My Father's Business (1988), a biography of Hugh Lynn Cayce (1907-1982).
- Box 1
  - address [Unity] Edgar Cayce, undated; Folder 1:1
  - brochure [Association of National Investigators], 1926; Folder 1:2
  - correspondence [Harmon Bro], 1982; Folder 1:3
  - correspondence, 1989-2009; Folder 1:4
  - diary notes [Gladys Davis Turner], 1934-1935; Folder 1:5
  - lectures [Atlantis: Symbol of Man's Forgotten Glory; Turning Point in World History; untitled at Willkie Memorial Hall] Hugh Lynn Cayce, 1950-1970; Folder 1:6
  - lectures [Edgar Cayce], 1930-1933; Folder 1:7
  - magazine [The Commonwealth: The Magazine of Virginia], August 1965; Folder 1:8
  - magazine [Psychic], September 1972; Folder 1:9
  - manuscript [Atlantis Revisited; Chapter 1] Edgar Evans Cayce, undated; Folder 1:10
  - manuscript [Edgar Cayce and the Church] Joseph Fitch, 1971; Folder 1:11
  - manuscript [Edgar Cayce's Memoirs] copy, 1932; Folder 1:12
  - manuscript [In Search of the Mother Pool: Correspondence between Edgar Cayce and Buddy Wilmott, December 1923-March 1926] Robert Krajenke, 1989; Folder 1:13
  - newsclippings, 1910-1945; Folder 1:14
  - notes, undated; Folder 1:15
- Box 2
  - outline and sample chapters [The Dayton Years] Robert Krajenke, undated; Folder 2:1
  - publications [A.R.E.], 1966-1981; Folder 2:2
  - report [Research Report on Edgar Cayce for ClearWindow Productions] Robert Krajenke; Stephan Schwartz; A. Robert Smith, 1990; Folder 2:3
  - research sources, 1982-1989; Folder 2:4
  - research sources [Fay Autry], 1987; Folder 2:5
  - research sources [death of Edgar Cayce], 1945; Folder 2:6
  - reviews [About My Father's Business], 1988-1989; Folder 2:7
  - screenplay [Miracle Man: The Edgar Cayce Story] A. Robert Smith, 1990; Folder 2:8
  - script [The Freak] Granville Burgess, 1981; Folder 2:9
  - transcript, interviews [Hugh Lynn Cayce], 1981-1982; Folder 2:10
  - transcript, interview [David Kahn], 1964; Folder 2:11